<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

    <meta name="keyword" content="captcha, java, core, jcaptcha"/>

    <body>
        <section name="Why JCaptcha?">
                            <p>
                                The consulting company i work for ( <a href="http://www.octo.com">OCTO Technology</a> ) was answering a RFP for the public administration in which a anti-bot submission protection was requiered.
 Nothing was available in java at the time, so we decided to write an Open Source implementation.
                            </p>
                        </section>

        <section name="Why a framework for Captcha?">

            <p>
Yes, why use a framework with hundreds of classes when some implementations are so simple?

To answer  this question lets imagine what happens when a captcha is cracked ie this is no more a hard AI problem.

                <ul>
                    <li>From scientific point of view</li>
                    <ul>
                        <li>This means computeur science has made a move a step forward in a precise field : for exemple Gimpy cracking involve new technics in the field of OCR.</li>
                        <li>Scientifics will have to invent a new, different, harder AI problem that human can easily solve and computers can't</li>
                        <li>The jcaptcha framework provides a common , high level language to defines those problems (the com.octo.captcha interface and typed derivatives)</li>

                    </ul>

                    <li>From a jcaptcha user point of view</li>
                    <ul>
                        <li>This means that his jcaptcha-ized application is may be vulnerable under bots attack</li>
                        <li>He will have to change the captcha in order to re protect his application</li>
                        <li>The jcaptcha framework provides simple way to parametrize new captchas (with engines and jcaptcha components)</li>
                    </ul>

                    <li>From a jcaptcha developper point of view</li>
                    <ul>
                        <li>This means he'll have to implement some new tests</li>
                        <li>He will have to implements a new captcha sub class, and to integrate it with the whole jcaptcha architecture</li>
                        <li>The jcaptcha framework clearly separates the services and integration facilities (service and modules subprojects) from the tests definitions and implementations (the core and engine sub projects)</li>
                    </ul>
                </ul>
            </p>

        </section>

    </body>
</document>
